原视频名：Can The Human Body Handle Rotating Artificial Gravity
原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/nxeMoaxUpWk
原视频发布日期：20210817
字幕翻译：旋火
Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
Today I want to talk to you about artificial gravity.
今天我想和你谈谈人工重力
Artificial gravity is of course a staple of science fiction.
人工重力当然是科幻小说的主要内容
Partly because if you're shooting a TV show or movie
部分原因是如果你在拍摄电视剧或电影时
it makes shooting scenes on earth a whole lot easier.
它使在地球上拍摄场景变得容易得多
But in the early days of spaceflight there were lots of concerns about the human body's reaction to Zero-G
但在航天飞行的早期 人们对人体对零重力的反应有很多担忧
to the point that
到了这样的程度
youtu.be/lfXi-7TtcYU
Yuri Gagarin would have to input a three-digit code to unlock the controls on Vostok 1
尤里·加加林不得不输入一个三位数的密码来解锁东方一号的控制装置
just in case being in Zero-G made him space crazy.
以防在零重力状态下使他在太空中发疯
While the first decade of human spaceflight showed that
虽然载人航天飞行的第一个十年表明
humans could easily adapt Zero-G for short missions
人类可以很容易地适应零重力的短期任务
there were many reasons to think that for longer missions say on space stations
有许多理由认为 对于较长的任务 例如在空间站上的任务
it would be a good idea to have access to artificial gravity capabilities
人工重力是一个好主意
for the sake of the long-term health of the crew
为了乘员的长期健康着想
specifically it was known even with a week or so of exposure
具体来说 人们知道 即使是在一个星期左右的(零重力环境)暴露中
that the human body will slowly lose muscle and bone mass in the absence of gravity.
人体在没有重力的情况下会慢慢失去肌肉和骨骼质量
On the engineering side of things
在工程方面的问题
the laws of physics give us three ways to generate gravity-style forces for a crew.
物理学定律给了我们三种方法来为乘员产生重力式的力
But only one of these is actually viable for spaceflight, rotational artificial gravity.
但其中只有旋转人工重力这一种方法对于航天飞行来说是实际可行的
You see gravity is a phenomenally weak phenomenon
你看 重力是一个非常弱的现象
and while science fiction loves artificial gravity generators in the floors of spacecraft
虽然科幻小说喜欢在航天器的地板上设置人工重力发生器
again because it makes it easy to shoot
也是因为这使它易于拍摄
and because it lets you design cool spaceships
也因为它能让你设计出很酷的宇宙飞船
there's nothing in the laws of physics that would imply or suggest that this is possible.
但是物理学定律中没有任何东西会暗示或表明这是可能的
The only way that we know right now to generate a gravity field is
我们现在知道的产生重力场的唯一方法是
with a huge amount of mass such as a planet.
用一个巨大的质量 如一个行星
Planet-sized chunks of mass are great for living on
行星大小的大块质量对于生活在上面的人来说是很好的
but they're kind of inconvenient to carry along if you're doing spaceflight.
但如果你要进行航天飞行的话 携带它就有点不方便了
Now another another way to do this is linear acceleration where you're going faster in a straight line
那么 另一种方法是线性加速 即你在一条直线上走得更快
and that does indeed generate the perception of real earth gravity.
而这确实产生了真实地球引力的感觉
Indeed Einstein built general relativity
事实上 爱因斯坦建立广义相对论
by assuming that accelerating in a straight line and planetary gravity
就是假设直线加速和行星引力
should be identical no experiment can tell them apart
应该是相同的 没有实验可以将它们区分开来
and guess what that works pretty well.
你猜怎么着 那是非常有效的
Now spaceflight is great for generating linear accelerations
那么 航天飞行对产生直线加速很有帮助
but you only get a few minutes during launch and re-entry.
但你只能在发射和再入大气层时得到几分钟这样的时间
Those chemical rocket engines can deliver the G-forces you need
那些化学火箭发动机可以提供你需要的过载力
but only for minutes before their propellant is depleted.
但只能维持几分钟 之后推进剂就耗尽了
In TV shows like the Expanse, the spacecraft use fusion drives
在像苍穹浩瀚 这样的电视剧中 航天器使用聚变发动机
that can accelerate for days on end without running out of propellant
可以连续几天加速而不会耗尽推进剂
but that's a technology that is driven by the needs of the plot
但这是一项由剧情需要驱动的技术
and it may never be possible with a human technology.
而人类的技术可能永远无法实现
Also the magnetic boots that we see in the show are again really nice if you're trying to shoot a TV show
此外 我们在剧中看到的磁靴也对电视剧友好
but they really just provide a way to secure your feet to the surface
但实际上这只是为脚固定在地面上提供了一种方法
without actually providing the gravity loads that make the human body work out and decondition.
而没有真正提供锻炼身体 保持身体健康的重力负荷
So rotational gravity is what's left, right.
因此 旋转重力是最终剩下的选择 对吧
That's the only one that's possible.
那是唯一可能的一种
And indeed the idea of large rotating space stations was around for decades
而且事实上 大型旋转空间站的想法已经存在几十年了
before anybody ever flew in space.
在任何人飞入太空之前
But a lifetime later and we still don't see rotating space stations
但是 一辈子的时间过去之后 我们仍然没有看到旋转的空间站
although there are many people who would love to build one such as the voyager space station.
尽管有许多人希望建立一个这样的空间站 如旅行者空间站
So a quick reminder of the math that this involves.
那么 快速说明一下这涉及的数学问题
If you have an object that is moving in a circle, you need a force pushing inwards towards the middle
如果你有一个在圆周上运动的物体 你需要一个向中间推的力
and that force has to be
而这个力必须是
proportional to the mass, the radius of the circle multiplied by the angular velocity squared
与质量 圆的半径以及角速度的平方的积成正比
and in physics we measure angular velocity in radians per second
而在物理学中 我们用弧度/秒来衡量角速度
so there's two Pi radians in a complete circle in 360 degrees.
因此 在一个完整的圆里有2π的弧度
So now if you want to generate an earth like 9.8 meters per second of gravity
那么如果你想产生类似地球上的重力 即9.8m/s²的加速度
with a 10 meter radius structure that's about 30 feet
使用半径为10米的结构(约为30英尺)
then you need to rotate it at about one radian per second or about 9.5 RPM.
那么你需要以大约每秒一个弧度或大约9.5转每分(RPM)的速度旋转它
If you make the radius longer then the rotation rate gets smaller
如果你让半径变长 那么旋转速度就会变小
and if you reduce the gravity that you want then similarly you can use lower rotation rates.
而如果你减少你想要的重力 那么同样地你可以使用较低的旋转速度
Now at this point I should put on my physics tutor hat
那么 在这一点上 我应该戴上我的物理学导师的帽子
其实只是不同的参考系下定义的力
and explain the difference between centripetal and centrifugal forces.
并解释一下向心力和离心力的区别
For an object to move in a circle
一个物体要想在一个圆里运动
it has to have that centripetal force pushing it towards the center of rotation
它必须有向心力把它推向旋转的中心
but if you are a person in a rotating space station with walls and you can't see out.
但如果你是在一个有墙的旋转空间站中的人 你看不到外面
What this force to you appears as the ground plate pushing up against you
这个力对你来说 就像地板推着你一样
you feel a centrifugal force pulling you down towards the floor.
你会感觉到一个离心力 把你拉向地面
And that feels like gravity
而这感觉就像重力
but this is different, equal and opposite
但这是不能等效 而且相反的
Look, it's different enough that it can serve as a limitless source of pedantry from physicists.
看 这个不同足以让它成为物理学家们无限卖弄学问的源泉
So anyway this kind of construction is of course used in training pilots and astronauts.
所以无论如何 这种结构当然是用于训练飞行员和宇航员的
You have the centrifuge facility.
这就是离心机设施
This is to give pilots a experience in high G loads on the ground.
这是为了让飞行员在地面上经受高过载力
You put them in a test cabin or a test car spin it around at high speeds
你把他们放在一个测试舱或测试车中 让它高速旋转
and generate the G-forces that they need to learn to handle
并产生他们需要学会应对的过载力
to make sure that the body is capable that the G suit works properly
以确保身体有能力承受 而抗荷服能正常工作
and just to teach them adaptation techniques to moments when they're dealing with this.
并教他们在处理这些问题时的适应技巧
But this kind of training is something that lasts for hours
但这种训练是持续几个小时的事情
rather than the weeks or months that astronauts might experience in the space station.
而不是像宇航员在空间站中可能经历的几周或几个月
So this kind of rotational facility is well understood by the spaceflight community
因此 这种旋转设施被航天界充分了解
and that meant that it was also known that there were side effects from spinning humans around like this.
而这意味着 人们也知道 像这样把人旋转会有副作用
I mean it's honestly something we learn as kids right.
我的意思是 说实话 这是我们从小就学到的东西吧
You get very dizzy if you spin around too fast
如果你旋转得太快 你会感到非常晕眩
and turning those childish understanding and perceptions of dizziness and falling over
并将这些对头晕和摔倒的幼稚的理解和看法
into quantifiable research on human physiology
变成可量化的人类生理学研究
is a serious endeavor that requires lots of effort, resources and dealing with people being sick.
是一项严肃的工作 需要大量的努力 资源以及处理人们呕吐的问题
So there's two main effects that we see when humans operate in a rotating environment.
因此 当人类在旋转的环境中运作时 我们看到有两个主要的影响
Firstly your body uses the semicircular canals near your ears to detect rotation
首先 你的身体使用你耳朵附近的半规管来检测旋转
and that helps you keep your balance.
并帮助你保持平衡
And they do this by detecting the motion of fluid in these sort of circular cavities.
而它们通过检测这些圆形腔体中液体的运动来实现这一目的
And this responds to the rotation of the of your head.
而其中的液体的运动是根据你头部的旋转而作出反应的
Now if you're sitting perfectly still your brain will take that as a non-moving reference frame
那么 如果你完全坐着不动 你的大脑会把它当作一个不移动的参考框架
and you'll stop getting dizzy if you're rotating.
而即使你在(匀速)旋转 也不会感到头晕
But if you're returning your head then you expect a certain rotation.
但是如果你回过头来 那么你就会期望有一定的旋转
If the room is turning and you turn your head you will get a different rotation
如果房间在转动 而你转动你的头 你会得到一个不同的旋转
and that will confuse your brain
而这将混淆你的大脑
and that will is a great way to give yourself motion sickness.
而这会让自己很容易头晕(动晕病)
One of the first things that people learn to do in rotational experiments
在旋转实验中 人们首先要学会做的事情之一
is to stop moving their head to minimize this effect.
是停止移动他们的头以减少这种影响
And the other thing is in a rotating environment any motion through that
另一件事是在一个旋转的环境中 任何通过该环境的运动
will frequently require forces that are different from the same motion in a non-rotating environment.
相比非旋转环境 会经常产生不同的力
These are broadly described as the coriolis forces
这些被广泛描述为科里奥利力
which at planetary scales affect the atmospheric motions
它在行星尺度上影响着大气运动
and help make tropical storms that rotate counterclockwise north of the equator
并有助于热带风暴在赤道以北逆时针旋转
and clockwise in the south.
而在南半球则是顺时针旋转
But at high rotation rates simply reaching out your hand to pick up something
但在高旋转率下 只要伸出手去拿东西
might result in the fictional coriolis force
都可能会导致虚拟的科里奥利力
pushing your arm away from the path that your brain has planned for.
将你的手臂推离你的大脑所规划的路径
Your brain is working with its previous experience
你的大脑正在用它以前的经验
and all your motor functions to balance this out.
和你所有的运动功能来平衡这一点
So when this happens your motor control system needs to re-learn how to perform these basic tasks
所以当这种情况发生时 你的运动控制系统需要重新学习这些基本任务的执行方法
and you can learn a specific motion really quickly minutes even.
那么你可以很快 甚至几分钟内 学会一个特定的动作
But then in some rotational environments
但是 在一些旋转环境中
if you turn to face a different direction or move your hand in a different direction
如果你转身面对一个不同的方向 或者将你的手向不同的方向移动
the coriolis force will again be different and you need further adaptation.
科里奥利力将再次变化 你需要进一步的适应
It takes days to become fully adapted to a rotating environment.
要想完全适应旋转环境 需要几天时间
So one question that scientists wanted to answer was
因此 科学家想要回答的一个问题是
what kind of rotation rates can the human body handle for long durations
什么类型的旋转率可以让人体长时间地承受
long enough to get over that initial sickness
足够长的时间来克服最初的眩晕感
long enough that the gravity would be needed to avoid deconditioning of the body.
足够长的时间 使得(人工)重力可以保持身体的健康
Can people perform at the same levels as they do in a non-rotating environment
人们能否在非旋转环境中发挥同样的水平？
or is there some penalty that can't be eliminated by training at any rotation rate.
还是有一些无论在任何旋转速率下 通过训练都无法消除的弊端
Is there an upper limit on the rotating conditions that human can handle.
人类所能处理的旋转条件是否有一个上限
Because that in turn if you've got a limit on your rotation rates
因为反过来 如果你对你的旋转率有一个限制的话
that will set the minimum radius for a spacecraft that is using rotational artificial gravity.
这将为使用旋转式人工重力的航天器设定最小半径
Now one of the problem with all the studies like this is that
那么 所有这样的研究的一个问题是
they're interested in hypothetical rotating structures in space.
他们对太空中的假想旋转结构感兴趣
But they have to take place on earth.
但是必须在地球上进行
And you can't subtract earth's gravity because we don't have anti-gravity
而且你不能减去地球的重力 因为我们没有反重力的设备
so one type of test is the rotating room where a room is rotated around its vertical axis like this
因此 一种类型的测试是旋转的房间 其中一个房间围绕其垂直轴旋转 就像这样
and you might actually have seen this on youtube.
而你可能真的在油管上看到过这个
There's a video with Tom Scott that does this.
有一个汤姆·斯科特的视频就是这样做的
But these have been around for a long time.
但这些已经存在了很长时间
The US Naval Medical Research Center built the slow rotating room facility in 1958
美国海军医学研究中心在1958年建造了一个慢速旋转的房间设施
that was like 10 meters across
它有10米宽
and they had living quarters in there for long duration testing
而他们在那里有生活区 用于长时间的测试
so people would live in there for weeks on end.
所以人们会在里面连续住上几个星期
At 1 RPM people could operate with very little adaptation
在1RPM的情况下 人们可以在很少的适应下操作
but most subjects would begin to suffer motion sickness initially
但(随着转速的提高) 大多数受试者会开始出现晕动症
when the room was spinning at about 3 RPM.
此时转速大概为3RPM
Again turning your head was the thing that would really trip off motion sickness
同样 转动你的头是会真正触发晕动症的事情
but from that people could adapt as you spun the room faster and faster
但在此基础上 当你把房间越转越快时 人们就能适应
and they could learn to handle much higher rotation rates even up to 10 RPM
而且他们可以学会应对更高的旋转速度 甚至达到10RPM
although quite a few people couldn't adapt and ended up making frequent use of the sick bags.
尽管有不少人仍无法适应 最后不得不频繁使用呕吐袋
Now in the Soviet Union again they did similar experiments using rotating rooms
那么在苏联 他们也用旋转的房间做了类似的实验
and they came to the same conclusions.
而且他们也得出了同样的结论
But the rotating room isn't the same as a spacecraft rotating to provide artificial gravity
但旋转室与航天器旋转以提供人工重力是不一样的
because the axis of rotation is in the spacecraft is parallel to the floor.
因为航天器的旋转轴是与地面平行的
But you can't do that on earth because of the ever-present gravity of the earth.
但在地球上你不能这样做 因为地球的重力一直存在
However there have been tests on large centrifuges
然而 已经对大型离心机进行了测试
with whole living spaces at the end with a rotation rate fast enough to incline the floor
在末端有整个生活空间 其旋转速度快到足以使地板倾斜
to provide a non-sloping surface for the occupants.
以便为居住者提供一个非倾斜的表面
And this means not only is the space rotating but you're also dealing with stronger gravity
而这意味着不仅空间在旋转 而且你还在处理更强的重力
so you had better be sure that you are not going to fall over
所以你最好确定你不会摔倒
because if you fall over due to your lack of balance
因为如果你由于缺乏平衡而摔倒了
you're going to hit the ground a lot harder in these environments.
在这些环境中 你将会更用力地撞击地面
So this footage here is from a Soviet experiment
因此 这段录像来自于苏联的一个实验
where again people would live for about a week at a time
在这个实验中 人们每次都会生活一个星期左右
and one of the more amusing demonstrations is the arrow throwing
其中一个更有趣的演示是扔箭的动作
where they curve around thanks to the coriolis force.
在那里 由于科里奥利力的作用 其轨迹会转弯
Although the elevator system is also another interesting thing
虽然电梯系统也是另一个有趣的东西
because you want to bring out the doctor to the crew to study them
因为你想把医生带到乘员那里去研究他们
but moving radial is really hard
但是径向移动是非常困难的
because your gravity forces and everything are rapidly changing as you move down this arm.
因为你的重力和一切都在迅速变化 因为你在这个悬臂上移动
It's one of the more disorienting experiences.
这是一个更加眩晕的感受
NASA also had a very large centrifuge system it's called the rotating test facility
NASA也有一个非常大的离心机系统 它被称为旋转测试设施
and it was built by Rockwell out in California
而它是由加州的罗克韦尔建造的
so on one side there was this living area it was like 40 feet long by 10 feet wide
所以在一侧有一个生活区 大概有12米长 3米宽
was actually a section of an aircraft apparently
实际上 显然是飞机的一个部分
and people would live in this for about a week at a time.
而人们会在这里面住上一个星期
The other side they counterbalanced this by having the walking wall
另一边 他们用步行墙来平衡这一点
and this was a vertical wall and they had straps to support people
这是一堵垂直的墙 使用带子来支撑人们的身体
so they could actually stand sideways on this
所以他们实际上可以侧身站在这上面
and test walking like let you prograde and or counter rotation, right.
并测试行走 比如在顺转或逆转的情况下 对吧
They could also use the same support harness system to simulate ascending and descending ladders
他们还可以用同样的支撑带系统来模拟上下梯子的动作
because again that's another thing that was quite complicated for your body to learn.
因为这也是另一件对你的身体来说相当复杂的事情 需要学习
实际上中国空间站也有，叫变重力实验机柜
But the only experiment I've seen that's really flown in space and provided artificial gravity is
但是我所看到的真正在太空中飞行并提供人工重力的唯一实验是
the Soviet Bion 3 or Kosmos 782 mission
苏联的生物体3或称宇宙782任务
so that had a small centrifuge on board it
那么 其搭载了一个小型离心机
and they had plants and animals in containers at different distances from the rotation axis
而他们把植物和动物放在离旋转轴不同距离的容器中
and that allowed them to compare different simulated gravitational environments.
这使他们能够比较不同的模拟重力环境
And as far as I can tell this is the most significant test of artificial gravity ever flown in space.
而就我所知 这是有史以来在航天飞行中的最重要的人工重力测试
It's also notable as the first time a US experiment flew on a Soviet space mission.
同样值得注意的是 这次是美国的实验第一次在苏联的航天任务中飞行
The spacecraft was actually based on the Zenith design
该航天器实际上是基于天顶号设计的
which was a Soviet photo reconnaissance satellite that
它是苏联的一颗照片侦察卫星
shared a lot in common with Vostok.
与东方号飞船有很多共同点
Because back in the 50s and 60s when Sergei Korolev was developing this
因为早在50年代和60年代 当谢尔盖·科罗廖夫在开发这个航天器时
he realized he could get money from the people that wanted a human spacecraft
他意识到他可以研制这样一种航天器 既可以赚载人航天器的钱
and from the people who wanted a spy satellite and build them one spacecraft, right.
也可以赚间谍卫星的钱 对吧
so yeah all of this stuff went on for decades
那么是的 所有这些研究都持续了几十年
and huge reports that were compiled for all these experiments
而所有这些实验都有大量的报告被汇编成册
and what they all basically say is slower is better.
而他们基本上都是说转得慢一点好
But rotational artificial gravity is possible in structures are comparable to the size of the ISS.
但是国际空间站大小的旋转人工重力是可能的
There would be a few engineering problems to solve to make sure like the thing remained balanced
这里面需要解决一些工程问题 比如平衡的保持
and you have your proper seals and transitions
以及适当的密封和过渡
but there's nothing insurmountable there.
但没有什么不可克服的问题
Instead we don't see rotating space stations
我们之所以没有看到旋转的空间站
because there's no real selling point
是因为没有真正的卖点
since the same intense medical research has helped develop ways
因为同样丰富的医学研究已经帮忙开发了一些方法
to stave off the deconditioning associated with Zero-G.
来避免身体机能的下降
Through consistent exercise to make up for the body not supporting your weight doing mundane things in Zero-G.
(比如)通过持续的锻炼来弥补在零重力中身体无法支持你做普通事情的状况
The ISS is primarily concerned with Zero-G research
国际空间站主要关注零重力的研究
and that kind of research is hard to do in a rotating station.
而这种研究在旋转空间站中很难进行
You would need a non-rotating section.
那样的话 需要一个非旋转部分
But the ISS does miss out on the ability to perform experiments at lower gravity levels than those on earth.
但是国际空间站确实失去了对低于地球重力实验的能力
I mean at one point there was a centrifuge facility planned for the ISS
我的意思是 曾经有一个为国际空间站计划的离心机设施
very similar to that found in the Bion 3 satellite.
与生物体3卫星中的设施非常相似
And that would allow small biological payloads to be exposed for lower gravity for long periods of time.
而这将允许小型生物有效载荷长时间暴露在较低的重力下
But ultimately this was cut to make the space station more affordable.
但这最终被砍掉了 来让国际空间站更加省钱
But with the new wave of space tourism
但随着新一轮太空旅游的兴起
there's suddenly a number of people who are interested in going into space
突然有许多人对进入太空感兴趣
and may find the idea of staying in space for a while taking in the views
并可能想要在太空中停留一段时间欣赏风景
and who don't need experiments that are in carefully controlled microgravity
而且他们不需要在精心控制的微重力条件下进行实验
so maybe the idea of a rotating space station will finally return.
因此 也许旋转式空间站的想法最终会重新出现
In the movie 2001: A Space Odyssey the rotating space station 5 at the start
在电影2001年：太空漫游 一开始的旋转的空间站5号
the interiors we get to see lounges restaurants and a hotel.
我们可以看到其内部的休息室 餐厅和一个酒店
It's not a science facility.
它不是一个科学设施
阿瑟·克拉克(Arthur Charles Clarke)，科幻小说2001太空漫游 的作者，也是同名电影的原作
So maybe the only thing Arthur C. Clarke got wrong was the date.
因此 也许阿瑟·克拉克唯一弄错的是日期
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]